<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experiment on Victor Alves</title>
    <link>/tags/experiment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experiment on Victor Alves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 15:53:26 -0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/experiment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/experimenting-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 15:53:26 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/experimenting-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;experimenting-with-hugo:bf73ee4053585d406df98173a6a435b8&#34;&gt;Experimenting with Hugo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my first post and I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about how I created the site. Last time I decided to create anything like a blog it was 1999. I&amp;rsquo;m used to work with dynamic webpages with database access upon request, since 1999 websites development has changed from static files only to dynamic webpages and now it&amp;rsquo;s coming back to static file again, to improve user experience by being as fast as it can possibly be. The difference from 1999&amp;rsquo;s website development, now a days we have tools to dynamically create static files and that&amp;rsquo;s what &lt;a href=&#34;//gohugo.oi/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; does. There are many other tools like Hugo, a popular choice is &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyllrb&lt;/a&gt;, I choose Hugo because it seemed simple and fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you want to see the original files I&amp;rsquo;m currently using for this experiment, I created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vhugo/vhugo.github.io-hugosrc&#34;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quickstart:bf73ee4053585d406df98173a6a435b8&#34;&gt;QuickStart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo has a good &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gohugo.io/overview/introduction/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gohugo.io/overview/quickstart/&#34;&gt;quickstart section&lt;/a&gt; you can create a website under 2 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/w7Ft2ymGmfc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you watch this video will know the basics to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes-and-layouts-files:bf73ee4053585d406df98173a6a435b8&#34;&gt;Themes and layouts files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the quickstart, I knew how to create site, add content and create site files, just needed to find a theme I like and start writing content. I wanted something clean and simple, so after looking at most of themes in &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Theme Showcase&lt;/a&gt; I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/cocoa/&#34;&gt;Cocoa&lt;/a&gt; developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nishanths&#34;&gt;Nishanth Shanmugham&lt;/a&gt;. To install it I just clone the repository into themes directory in the project root directory. It looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd project-root-dir
git clone https://github.com/nishanths/cocoa-hugo-theme.git themes/cocoa
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the theme is good, I still wanted to make some changes without touching the original source, so I added some new files into &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vhugo/vhugo.github.io-hugosrc/tree/master/layouts&#34;&gt;layouts folder&lt;/a&gt;  which is used instead of the ones in the theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;github-pages:bf73ee4053585d406df98173a6a435b8&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I publish the site using Github, I just created a new repo called &lt;code&gt;vhugo.github.io&lt;/code&gt; and push all files from my Hugo project&amp;rsquo;s public folder. if you want to know more about this check &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;editors-for-code-and-markdown-content:bf73ee4053585d406df98173a6a435b8&#34;&gt;Editors for code and markdown content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a developer I love text editors of all kind, but don&amp;rsquo;t like fancy IDEs as much. For years I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://macromates.com/&#34;&gt;TextMate&lt;/a&gt; and when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com/&#34;&gt;SublimeText&lt;/a&gt; showed up and I felt the need to switch editors, been using it ever since. There&amp;rsquo;s a new editor emerging from the GitHub team called &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, still miss a lot of packages that I&amp;rsquo;m used to on SublimeText, but it looks promising. SublimeText has some packages to help edit markdown, but I found a MarkDown editor called &lt;a href=&#34;http://writed.io/&#34;&gt;Writed&lt;/a&gt;, loved it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>