<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Victor Alves</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Victor Alves</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 04:49:23 -0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ruby on Rails development environment with Docker</title><link>/posts/ruby-on-rails-development-environment-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 04:49:23 -0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/ruby-on-rails-development-environment-with-docker/</guid><description>Learning Ruby and Rails This was how I created my first project to learn more about Ruby and Rails, I decided to create a web application for photo gallery. For starter, I wanted to keep my dev env isolated and more controlled, reason why I opt to use Docker, I had it already installed, as well as Ruby and Rails.
I created the new project with rails new --skip-bundle gallery on my workstation, used --skip-bundle because I'm going to install all Gems in the container, it added all the files and folder I needed to start my Rails project, then I added everything into a Git repository, just to keep track of my steps.</description></item><item><title>How I made a static photo gallery for Hugo</title><link>/posts/how-i-made-a-static-photo-gallery-for-hugo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 07:25:15 -0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-i-made-a-static-photo-gallery-for-hugo/</guid><description>updated: I've named this project Hugallery and I share and maintain its code at Github, if you're interested go check it out. Also the README.md file looks way better and up-to-date than this articles.
Goal Create a command-line program that generate a static web photo gallery based on a given directory with raw photos files.
Planning Things I want to accomplish in this project:
It must be easy to install and use; It must be easy to configure and define or modify the gallery structure; It must be reusable for existing galleries; It should create file compatible with HUGO standards; Workflow Each album should have 2 configuration file album.</description></item><item><title>Experimenting with Hugo</title><link>/posts/experimenting-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 15:53:26 -0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/experimenting-with-hugo/</guid><description>Experimenting with Hugo This is my first post and I'm going to talk about how I created the site. Last time I decided to create anything like a blog it was 1999. I'm used to work with dynamic webpages with database access upon request, since 1999 websites development has changed from static files only to dynamic webpages and now it's coming back to static file again, to improve user experience by being as fast as it can possibly be.</description></item></channel></rss>